Rohit Wagh Senior Security Analyst (L2)

+91 7276999464

rohitwagh4145@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rpwagh

• Pune (MH)

₽ Profile

Senior Security Analyst (L2) with 3.7 years of proven experience in protecting IT systems and infra. Expertise in **Endpoint Security** tools such as Microsoft Defender EDR. Intune and **Trellix Endpoint Proficient** Security (AV). safeguarding data through Microsoft Purview DLP and Trellix FRP. problem-solving Strong communication skills with the ability to deliver successful projects.

Education

B.E. in Ele and Tele Engg,

Shri Sant Gajanan Maharaj College of Engineering, Shegaon. Aug 2016 – Oct 2020 | Buldana, India

Technical Skills

Trellix ePO | Trellix ENS | Trellix FRP | Trellix DLP | Microsoft Defender EDR Microsoft Intune | VirusTotal | Phishing Email Investigation Microsoft Purview DLP | Incident Response | MS Office | ServiceNow ITSM | Solve ITSM | Good Communication & Presentation skills | Giving KTs

Certifications

CompTIA Security + | SC-900 | AZ-900 | MS-900 | SC-400 | AWS Cloud Practitioner Purdue ACE Malware & Threat Hunting | Purdue ACE Specialist

Awards

C-LIFE Champion (Client Value) Infosys Limited

Mar 2024

Insta Award (EPS Contribution)

Infosys Limited Nov 2024

Professional Experience

Infosys Limited

Senior Systems Engineer (Security Analyst L2)

Jul 2024 – present | Pune, India

- Microsoft Defender EDR, Microsoft Intune, Trellix (formerly McAfee) ENS, Trellix FRP, VirusTotal, ServiceNow ITSM

Systems Engineer (Security Analyst L1)

Mar 2022 – Jun 2024 | Pune, India

- Microsoft Defender EDR, Microsoft Purview DLP, Trellix ENS, Trellix FRP, VirusTotal, ServiceNow ITSM

Hindustan Aeronautics Limited

GAT - Endpoint Security Administrator (L1)

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022 | Nasik, India

Trellix Endpoint Security (AV), Trellix Data Loss Prevention, In-house ITSM Software

Projects

Client - A Global Leader in Automotive Industry

Domain - Endpoint Security

- Conducted regular ePO health checks, ensuring 100% system compliance and optimal endpoint protection.
- Monitored and resolved alerts and incident queues in Microsoft Defender resolving issues promptly.
- Deployed, managed and troubleshot Trellix ENS/VSE/FRP (formerly **McAfee**) components for 40,000+ endpoints.
- Implemented change management processes for testing, onboarding and deploying AV products as well as creating exclusion policies.
- Prepared and maintained IIDs, KBs, SOPs and technical overview documents to support process improvement based on client requirements.
- Coordinated with stakeholders (Infra, Service Desk and Support teams) to manage, resolve and escalate incidents efficiently.
- Generated and delivered weekly and monthly performance analysis metrics reports to client leadership, contributing to strategic decision-making.
- Worked as a shared resource across multiple global projects, ensuring seamless security operations and compliance.

Client - A Global Leader in Automotive Industry

Domain - Data Loss Prevention

- Configured and optimized Microsoft Purview DLP to effectively monitor, detect and prevent data leaks.
- Implemented and managed DLP policies; monitored and investigated DLP alerts.

Client - A Leader in the Indian Aerospace and Defense Industry

Domain - Endpoint Security

- Administered, managed and troubleshot antivirus infrastructures including Trellix Agent, VirusScan Enterprise and DLP for 10000+ systems.
- Delivered **end-to-end support for antivirus solutions** and updated virus definitions.
- Manual and scheduled deployment of Trellix endpoint products to all the systems and servers in the infrastructure.